Muhammad Ahmad

Pakistan



muhammadahmad.soft@outlook.com



03122022760



linkedin.com/in/muhammad-ahmad-3aa370a2

Summary

7+ years of software development, integration and mobile application experience. Experience in analysis, design, development and testing of web based n-tier applications. Experience in Xamarin and Microsoft .NET technologies .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET, API, MVC, Win Forms, ADO.NET, Enterprise Library etc. Experience in database design and development using Microsoft SQL Server 2008R2, 2012. Experience in client side development using JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, HTML, CSS etc. Excellent in troubleshooting techniques. Having good problem solving and analytical skills. Highly motivated team player, who has ability to perform confidently and effectively under pressure and thrives on challenge. Enthusiastic learner, able to grasp concepts and technical skills quickly. Ability to work both independently and in team environment

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Matech Consulting & Outsourcing

Nov 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

During the time I worked on different projects on different roles, manly worked on logistic projects. Worked as team lead on a project based on technologies like Dot Net Core ,Angular and RDLC Reporting with My SQL DB.

Worked on MVC Dot Net as Full stack, Partly worked on a project for 3rd party integrations.

Senior Software Developer

Eiwan

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 3 months)

During the tenure I worked on all parts of SDLC for the company from requirement gathering to to design Project flow and Data Base according to the provided Business knowledge, worked with banks for Payment integrations.

My responsibilities include Managing development Processes and manage other developers, provide technical assistance to performing there tasks.

Android Developer

The Roots International

Sep 2017 - Nov 2019 (2 years 3 months)

During the time with The Roots International I Worked as a Mobile Developer.

My additional responsibilities are to work with business team for there technical assistance and manage outsourced resources for the company.

>>> Dot Net Developer

Excelsious

Nov 2016 - Jul 2017 (9 months)

During the period, as .Net developer I worked all most all areas of software development life cycle partially

design, analysis, development, implementation, testing and deployment of web based multi-tier application .

Worked on WCF restful service development and implementation, 3rd party financial apps Integration like QBO and Xero , MVC, .Net Entity framework , WPF.



Web & Mobile Developer

click9

Aug 2013 - Aug 2016 (3 years 1 month)

Worked on Single handed projects like Approval Management System and School Management system .Main Achievement of job is to work on new hybrid mobile platform Xamarin .Develop application for a Bank .

My main responsibilities includes requirement gathering, application development, deployment, maintenance and support.

Education



APTECH

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Programming, Specific Applications 2012 - 2015

Skills

ASP.NET MVC • .NET Core • ASP.NET Web API • jQuery • Mobile Applications • Git • Leadership • Active Learning • Databases • Angular